The factory model of machine learning is
an allegory or a framework that I think describes
well how to bootstrap a system into high-performance with data.
The factory really is a mapping between data
set and outcome a model you want that does your job.
But it's usually not quite so simple.
Typically, the process is cyclical.
You start by collecting a data set on a task you want,
send part of it for labeling.
Take these labels and create a model.
Evaluate this model, find shortcomings,
and decide potentially what other data needs to be collected or labeled.
Perform that, collect this version 2 of the data set and repeat.
This is a environment and infrastructure in a pipeline that once established,
can keep churning models for you and close this virtuous loop.
In typical industry we see over many generations,
your models keep getting better and better and better.
Even though it takes a non-trivial investment in setting up all this infrastructure,
that it does a lot of work for you.